## **Emelin E. Flores**

■ (201) 745 9960 ■ emelinfloress@gmail.com ■

An information technology student who wants to do the best and make an impact on the community. I am a self-starter who is motivated, friendly, and a quick learner with 2+ years of project management, programming, and marketing experience. In addition, I am a down-to-earth leader with the ability to sustain a personal and professional atmosphere.

Education
Rutgers University
Douglass Women's College

B.S., Information Technology Informatics Minor Critical Intelligence Studies

Codecademy

Full Stack Pro Intensive Course May 2018-Present

Skills

Google APIs(beginner)

Bootstrap(intermediate)

• Java(beginner)

Microsoft Excel & Office

HTML/CSS(intermediate)

• Database Management

- Spanish working proficiency
- Python(intermediate)
- Adobe Photoshop/Premiere

<u>Internships</u>

NJ Tech Council - Data Analyst Intern

January 2019

Class of 2020

- Analyzed startup companies from the tri-state area to help create reports of startup companies for the upcoming Venture event
- Analyzed data from Women In Tech conferences over the years to present to the board of the organization to determine the success of all women events
- Analyzed social media trends over the past year to determine where the company has the best online presence

**Hudson County Department of Welfare - Project Coordinator Intern** 

June 2016- Aug 2016

- Mentored ~30 students to take on part-time summer employment opportunities within Hudson County and supported them by checking up on them via performance evaluation and resolved conflict or concern
- Maintained records and contact information for part-time summer employees to determine hiring pool for subsequent years and expense data accounting

**Work Experience** 

Web Developer + IT Specialist - Vintage Vinyl Records Ford, NJ

May 2018 - Present

- Created a web developer training program to help other developers transition to the frameworks used/solve common issues
- Optimized newsletter responsiveness on several platforms like desktop, laptop, or mobile phones. The newsletter is also responsive to different emailing platforms that do not disrupt the content
- Minimized costs of newsletter online marketing by saving \$2000/year of the cost to market by switching to a different, more efficient provider

**Research Projects and Interests** 

ByteHacks (Hackathon) MishApps - Python, CSS, Adobe XD, HTML, CSS, Twilio 3rd Place

September 2018

- Developed a local and global natural disaster alert system using Twilio, Python, Adobe XD, HTML, and CSS that placed in 3rd
- Led a team of 5 to complete this project from research, planning, and implementation
- Cleaned CSS for the web page and organizing the backend which included python scripts that prompted a Twilio API

**Growup Cannabis Hackathon** - ReactJS, Python, Wit.ai

2nd Place

September 2018

- Led the team that developed a Natural Language Understanding web app that users can speak to and receive information about their data sets. It is a similar concept to a virtual assistant (Amazon Alexa, Google Home)
- Developed a web app to parse data for inquiries, receive useful insight using predictive analysis, and make changes to the database

**Extracurricular Activities** 

Mentee - #BUILTBYGIRL Wave Program

Sept. 2018 - Present

• One-year mentorship commitment meeting new mentor every 3 months. Mentors from different companies, like Google, Microsoft and other top startups or tech companies

Volunteer - Queens College Hackathon

**April 2019** 

Teached an introduction to natural language processing workshop for hackathon participants

Links

Website - https://floresemelin.github.io/

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/emelinflores01/